[
  {
    "question": "Venus is the _________ planet from the sun.",
    "options": [
      "third",
      "second",
      "fourth"
    ],
    "correct": "second"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is named after roman godess of ____ and _______.",
    "options": [
      "love and peace.",
      "care and beauty.",
      "love and beauty."
    ],
    "correct": "love and beauty."
  },
  {
    "question": "After moon venus is the second _________ object on the dark sky.",
    "options": [
      "brightest",
      "shiniest",
      "spotted"
    ],
    "correct": "brightest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Venus is reffered as the earths __________ planet.",
    "options": [
      "mother",
      "brother",
      "sister"
    ],
    "correct": "sister"
  },
  {
    "question": "The surface of the planet has the clouds made of _________.",
    "options": [
      "acetic acid",
      "chloric acid",
      "sulphuric acid"
    ],
    "correct": "sulphuric acid"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the diameter of the planet?",
    "options": [
      "<10000",
      "<6000",
      "<13000"
    ],
    "correct": "<13000"
  },
  {
    "question": "The orbit period is ________.",
    "options": [
      "225",
      "255",
      "245"
    ],
    "correct": "225"
  },
  {
    "question": "Surface temperature is about _____.",
    "options": [
      "123C",
      "324C",
      "462C"
    ],
    "correct": "462C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Venus is as big as which planet?",
    "options": [
      "mercury",
      "earth",
      "jupiter"
    ],
    "correct": "earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many earth days is equal to a day in venus?",
    "options": [
      "114",
      "117",
      "115"
    ],
    "correct": "117"
  },
  {
    "question": "A year on venus is equal to _______ earth days.",
    "options": [
      "223",
      "224",
      "225"
    ],
    "correct": "225"
  },
  {
    "question": "A _________ on venus can last longer than a year.",
    "options": [
      "hour",
      "day",
      "month"
    ],
    "correct": "day"
  },
  {
    "question": "The atmosperic pressure on venus is ______times greater than earth.",
    "options": [
      "92",
      "95",
      "99"
    ],
    "correct": "92"
  },
  {
    "question": "Venus is also know as the ____________ and ___________ star.",
    "options": [
      "morning and afternoon",
      "afternoon and evening",
      "morning and evening"
    ],
    "correct": "morning and evening"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who sent the first mission to venus?",
    "options": [
      "german",
      "russian",
      "persian"
    ],
    "correct": "russian"
  }
]